# **Winston Summers**

### Web Developer

SDE I excited to grow on existing skill sets and bring value to the team and company. Excelling at researching problems to find solutions, not giving up until the job is done.

Experienced leading small teams and training new hires; when a deadline needs to be met, I am frequently the one management comes to to lead the charge. Communication is one of my most valuable assets; a skill that I have refined on the job, working with clients and colleagues alike.



### **Education**

## 2017-11 - General Assembly, Web Development Imersive

2018-02

Wrote HTML, CSS, and JavaScript that displayed as intended in modern browsers

Developed back-end web applications and API's using cutting-edge features from ES6 and ExpressJS or Python3 and Django

Developed dynamic front-ends to applications using modern frameworks like ReactJs to create single-page apps

Utilized web APIs from third-party sites like Twitter or Yelp

Wrote secure applications and deployed them to cloud services like Heroku Collaborated within teams using agile development workflow and widely-accepted collaboration practices using Git

Designed responsive web applications

Built secure full-stack web applications according to common design patterns
Used modern JavaScript browser application frameworks like ReactJs
Safely modeled and stored data in SQL and NoSQL databases
Developed web applications using both Python and JavaScript



## **Experience**

### 2016-12 - Materials Handler

2017-11

Synrad

Trained short term and long term employees on job requirements and safety procedures

Prioritized and managed time to accomplish many tasks on varying time lines Communicated in close teams to handle the needs of other departments to produce product

Input and tracked inventory to manage loss control using Oracle 12 Discuss goods and services information with customers or patrons Compile data and documentation



#### **Address**

Seattle, WA

#### **Phone**

(425)551-0004

#### E-mail

winstonsummers@live.com

#### Github

https://github.com/winstonsummers

#### LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/winston -summers/

### Portfolio

https://winstonsummers.github.io/N ew-Portfolio/



Git/Github, ReactJs, JSON

Advanced

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, NoSQL, Python, NodeJs, PostgreSQL, Django, Jquery, MongoDB

Fluent

SQL, RESTful APIs, AJAX, Java

**Proficient**